惯性测量单元的最后一个部件是测量角速度的传感器，
The final component of the inertia measurement unit are the sensors that measure angular velocity,
这些通常被称为陀螺仪。你可能有一个陀螺仪
and these are commonly referred to as gyroscopes. You might have had a gyroscope
作为一个玩具，当你还是个孩子的时候，很难理解它们之间的关系
as a toy when you were a child, and it is difficult to understand the relationship between
这个玩具陀螺仪，可以在铅笔的末端与可以测量的设备平衡
this toy gyroscope, which can balance on the end of a pencil with a device that can measure
角速度。要了解我们如何将陀螺仪用作角速度传感器，
angular velocity. To understand how we can use a gyroscope as an angular velocity sensor,
我们需要回到纺纱机构的基本原理。在这里，我们有一张光盘
we need to get right back to fundamentals of spinning bodies. Here, we have a disc which
围绕虚线所示的轴旋转，它以角速度旋转，
is spinning about the axis shown by the dotted line, and it is spinning with an angular velocity,
欧米茄和圆盘有转动惯量，j。我们指的是角动量
omega g and the disc has got a rotational inertia, j. We refer to the angular momentum
这个光盘，并给出符号h。h是j次欧米茄。现在，我们来吧
of this disc and give that the symbol h. h is j times omega g. Now, let's
想象一下，我对这个旋转盘施加扭矩。如果我这样做，光盘想要旋转
imagine that I apply a torque to this rotating disc. If I do that, the disc wants to rotate
关于蓝色箭头所示的轴。它是矢量h和的交叉积
about the axis shown by the blue arrow. It's the cross product of the vector h and
矢量Tau。
the vector Tau.
我们这里有一个陀螺仪，目前，我们可以旋转设备
What we have here is a gyroscope and at the moment, the device is not spinning we can
看到它在万向节机构内部非常自由和漂亮地移动。如果我转动电机
see that it moves very freely and nicely inside its gimbal mechanism. If I turn the motor
现在，需要一点时间才能达到速度，现在表现得非常不同。
on, it takes a little moment to come up to speed, it now behaves very very differently.
现在，我将围绕蓝色箭头转动旋转盘组件，现在;该
Now, I'm going to rotate the spinning disc assembly about the blue arrow and now; the
旋转盘将围绕红色箭头施加扭矩，并且该扭矩是十字形
spinning disc is going to exert a torque about the red arrow, and that torque is the cross
矢量欧米茄和h的产物。那么，我该如何测量扭矩呢？如果光盘
product of the vectors omega and h. So, how do I measure the torque? If the disc
然后，轴由两个轴承支撑，该扭矩将在一个轴承上施加一个力
axis is supported by two bearings then, this torque will exert a force up on one bearing
并且在另一个轴承上，可以测量这些力。旋转盘然后有
and down on the other bearing, and those forces can be measured. The spinning disc then has
将角速度Ω转换成扭矩，然后用力测量
converted the angular velocity omega into a torque which is then, measured using force
传感器。
sensors.
重要的是，如果我用橡皮筋拉动陀螺仪的这个轴，我基本上就是这样
Importantly, if I pull on this axis of the gyroscope with a rubber band, I am basically
要对它施加压力。所以，我拉着这个方向。你会看到陀螺仪
going to exert a force on it. And so, I pull in this direction. You will see that the gyroscope
试图绕这样的轴旋转。
is trying to rotate about an axis like this.
基于旋转盘的角速度传感器不再常见。他们倾向于
Angular velocity sensors based on spinning discs are not very common anymore. They tend
相当笨重，需要很大的力量来保持光盘旋转。传感器今天
to be rather bulky and require a lot of power to keep that disc spinning. Sensors today
是基于振动而不是旋转元件，但我们仍倾向于称它们为陀螺仪
are based on vibrating rather than rotating element, but we still tend to call them gyroscopes
或陀螺仪传感器。振动元件采用“MEMS”技术制造。
or gyroscopic sensors. The vibrating elements are fabricated using ‘MEMS’ technology.
因此，传感元件本身的尺寸是微观的，但其基本原理是
So, the sensing elements themselves are microscopic in size but the underlying principle is the
相同。传感器中的角速度导致力或力矩施加在微型上
same. Angular velocity in the sensor causes forces or torques to be exerted on the micro
尺度元素，导致位移，可以测量和放大产生
scale elements and that leads to displacements, which can be measured and amplified to produce
角速度信号。与加速度计和磁力计一样，包装也很常见
an angular velocity signal. As with accelerometers and magnetometers it is very common to package
三个陀螺仪传感器组成一个芯片，它们再次正交排列
three gyroscope sensors into a single chip, and they are arranged orthogonally again so
它们测量角速度矢量的三个分量。就像你有加速度计一样
they measure the three components of the angular velocity vector. Just as you have accelerometers
在你的脑海里，你的头上也有陀螺仪，再一次，这些都在你的头上
in your head, you also have gyroscopes in your head and once again, these are in the
内耳组件。特别是三个非常有特色的元素称为半圆形
inner ear assembly. In particular, the three very distinctive elements known as the semi-circular
运河。这些是非常细的管子，充满了液体和头部的旋转运动
canals. These are very thin tubes filled with fluid and rotational motion of your head causes
这些管中的液体移动。微小的毛细胞检测到液体的运动
the liquid in those tubes to move. The motion of a fluid is detected by tiny hair cells
在运河内，这会导致大脑出现角速度信号。角度
within the canals, and this leads to an angular velocity signal to your brain. The angular
速度信号与来自您眼睛的运动信息相结合。如果这两个信号
velocity signal is combined with motion information that comes from your eyes. If these two signals
不一致，它导致我们作为晕动病的问题，那就是
are not consistent, it leads to a problem which we experience as motion sickness, that's
当我们的内耳告诉我们我们的身体在某种程度上正在移动时，但我们的眼睛却在说
when our inner ear is telling us that our body is moving in one way, but our eyes tell
我们，我们的身体以不同的方式运动。所以，这是晕车病或晕船病，
us that our body is moving in a different way. So, this is motion sickness or sea sickness,
我们的身体想要让我们呕吐，反应不合逻辑。
and our body responds rather illogically by wanting us to throw up.